<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shih-Yun Tang</title>
    <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shihyuntang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shih-Yun Tang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2018-2024 Shih-Yun Tang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shihyuntang.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Shih-Yun Tang</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Basic</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/1-some-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/1-some-basic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-terminology-in-statistics&#34;&gt;Some Terminology in Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;i.i.d. (Independent and Identically Distributed):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; This term refers to a set of random variables that are all independent of each other and share the same probability distribution. The assumption of i.i.d. is crucial in many statistical methods because it simplifies the mathematical analysis and inference processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Null Hypothesis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; In hypothesis testing, the null hypothesis is a general statement or default position that there is no relationship between two measured phenomena or no association among groups tested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P-value:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; The p-value is the probability of observing test results at least as extreme as the results actually observed, under the assumption that the null hypothesis is correct. A p-value less than a pre-determined significance level, often 0.05, leads to the rejection of the null hypothesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidence Interval (CI):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; A confidence interval is a range of values, derived from sample statistics, that is likely to contain the value of an unknown population parameter. The confidence level represents the probability that this interval will capture this parameter in repeated samples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type I and Type II Errors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type I Error (False Positive):&lt;/strong&gt; Occurs when the null hypothesis is incorrectly rejected when it is actually true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type II Error (False Negative):&lt;/strong&gt; Occurs when the null hypothesis is not rejected when it is actually false.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-and-second-moments&#34;&gt;First and Second Moments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In probability and statistics, the concepts of first and second moments are central to understanding the distributions of random variables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Moment (Mean):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; The first moment is the expected value of a random variable $X$, denoted as $E(X)$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt;
$$E(X) = \mu$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Moment (Variance):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; The second moment about the mean is the variance of the random variable $X$, denoted as $\sigma^2$. It measures the spread of the data points around the mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt; The variance is calculated using the expectation of the &lt;em&gt;squared deviations from the mean&lt;/em&gt;:
$$
\sigma^2 = E[(X-\mu)^2] = E[X^2] - E(X)^2
$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}
\sigma^2 &amp;amp;= E[(X-\mu)^2] \\
&amp;amp;= E[X^2 - 2X\mu + \mu^2] \\
&amp;amp;= E[X^2] - 2\mu E(X) + E(\mu^2) \\
&amp;amp;= E[X^2] - 2\mu^2 + \mu^2 \\
&amp;amp;= E[X^2] - \mu^2 \\
&amp;amp;= E[X^2] - E(X)^2
\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Moment (Skewness):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; The third central moment describes the skewness of the distribution of a random variable, indicating the degree of asymmetry around the mean. Skewness can reveal whether the distribution tails off more on one side than the other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt; The third moment is calculated using the expectation of the cubed deviations from the mean:
$$
E[(X - E(X))^3]
$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/strong&gt; A positive skewness indicates that the distribution has a long tail to the right (more positive side), while a negative skewness indicates a long tail to the left (more negative side).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Covariance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; Covariance measures the joint variability of two random variables, $X$ and $Y$. It assesses the degree to which two variables change together. If the greater values of one variable mainly correspond to the greater values of the other variable, and the same holds for the lesser values, the covariance is positive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt; The covariance between two variables $X$ and $Y$ is given by:
$$
\text{Cov}(X, Y) = E[(X - E(X))(Y - E(Y))]
$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/strong&gt; A positive covariance indicates that as $X$ increases, $Y$ tends to increase. A negative covariance suggests that as $X$ increases, $Y$ tends to decrease. Zero covariance indicates that the variables are independent, assuming they are also uncorrelated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;standardization&#34;&gt;Standardization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transforming the random variable to with zero mean and unit variance. This tranasformation also removes the unit on the random variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
X_{std} = \frac{X - \mu}{\sigma}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;z-test-vs-t-test&#34;&gt;z test vs. t test&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributions</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/2-probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/2-probability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;probability-distributions&#34;&gt;Probability Distributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probability distributions describe how the probabilities of a &lt;strong&gt;random variable&lt;/strong&gt; are distributed. Here are the two main types of probability functions associated with these distributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probability Density Function (PDF, continuous):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The PDF is used to specify the probability of a random variable falling within a particular range of values, rather than taking any one specific value. This function is applicable only to continuous variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Characteristic:&lt;/strong&gt; The area under the PDF curve between two points represents the probability of the variable falling within that range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The normal distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probability Mass Function (PMF, discrete):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The PMF is used for discrete random variables and specifies the probability that a random variable is exactly equal to some value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Characteristic:&lt;/strong&gt; The sum of all the probabilities represented by the PMF must equal 1, as it accounts for every possible discrete value the variable can take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; The binomial distribution, and the Poisson distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cumulative Distribution Function (CDF):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt; The CDF is used to determine the probability that a random variable (X) is $\lesssim$ to a certain value. CDF can be applied to both discrete and continuous random variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Characteristic:&lt;/strong&gt; The CDF is a non-decreasing function that ranges from 0 to 1. For continuous variables, it is obtained by integrating the PDF over the range of possible values. For discrete variables, it is the cumulative sum of the PMF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; For normal distribution, the CDF is used to calculate the probability that the variable is less than a specific threshold, which is central to hypothesis testing and confidence interval estimation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chebyshevs-theorem&#34;&gt;Chebyshev&amp;rsquo;s Theorem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chebyshev&amp;rsquo;s Theorem, also known as Chebyshev&amp;rsquo;s Inequality, is a fundamental result in probability theory that provides a way &lt;strong&gt;to estimate the probability that a random variable differs from its mean&lt;/strong&gt;. This theorem is not restricted to normally distributed data, making it very versatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theorem Statement:&lt;/strong&gt;
$$
P(|X-\mu| &amp;lt; k\sigma) \geq 1 - \frac{1}{k^2}
$$
where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;($\mu$) is the mean of the random variable ( X ),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;($\sigma$) is the standard deviation of ( X ),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;($k$) is a positive number greater than 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generality:&lt;/strong&gt; Chebyshev&amp;rsquo;s theorem applies to any probability distribution where the mean and variance are defined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implication:&lt;/strong&gt; The inequality tells us that no matter the shape of the distribution, the proportion of values that fall within ($k$) standard deviations of the mean is at least $( 1 - \frac{1}{k^2})$. For example, at least (75%) of the values lie within 2 standard deviations of the mean (since ($k=2$) gives $( 1-\frac{1}{4} = 0.75)$).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitations:&lt;/strong&gt; While the theorem provides a lower bound, it does not give exact probabilities, and the bounds can be quite loose, especially for distributions that tightly clustered around the mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chebyshev&amp;rsquo;s Theorem is particularly useful for analysts and statisticians dealing with samples from unknown distributions, as it provides a safe, conservative estimate of the spread of data around the mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discrete-distributions&#34;&gt;Discrete Distributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;binomial-distribution&#34;&gt;Binomial Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Binomial distribution is a discrete probability distribution that models the number of successes in a fixed number of independent trials, with each trial having two possible outcomes, typically labeled as &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;failure&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are only two possible outcomes for each trial: success (1) and failure (0).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The trials are independent, meaning the outcome of one trial does not affect the outcomes of other trials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The probability mass function (PMF) for the Binomial distribution is expressed as:
$$
P(X=x) = C^{n}_{x} \theta^x (1-\theta)^{n-x}
$$
where $\theta$ is the probability of success on a single trial, $x$ is the number of successes, and $n$ is the total number of trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
Consider flipping a fair coin five times. What is the probability of getting exactly two heads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calculation is as follows:
$$
P(X=2) = C^{5}_{2} 0.5^2 (1-0.5)^3 = \frac{5!}{2!3!} \times 0.25 \times 0.125 = 31.25%
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;geometric-distribution&#34;&gt;Geometric Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geometric distribution describes the probability of observing the first success on the $x$-th trial in a sequence of Bernoulli trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PMF:&lt;/strong&gt;
$$
g(x; \theta) = \theta(1-\theta)^{x-1}
$$
where, $\theta$ is the probability of success on each trial, and $x$ is the trial number of the first success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Properties:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean ($\mu$):&lt;/strong&gt; The expected number of trials to get the first success is given by:
$$
\mu = \frac{1}{\theta}
$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variance ($\sigma^2$):&lt;/strong&gt; The variance of the number of trials to get the first success is:
$$
\sigma^2 = \frac{1-\theta}{\theta^2}
$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interpretation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mean and variance provide insights into the &amp;ldquo;spread&amp;rdquo; or variability of trials needed to achieve the first success, with higher values of $\theta$ leading to fewer expected trials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distribution is commonly used in &lt;em&gt;quality control&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;reliability testing&lt;/em&gt;, and other areas where the &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; or number of trials until the first success is of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;poisson-distribution&#34;&gt;Poisson Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Poisson distribution is a discrete probability distribution that expresses the probability of a given number of events occurring within a fixed interval of time or space. It assumes these events occur with a known constant mean rate and independently of the time since the last event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A practical example is photometry using a Charge-Coupled Device (CCD), where light—specifically, the number of photons—hits the CCD at a constant rate. Importantly, the arrival of photons is assumed to be independent of previous arrivals, provided the CCD is not saturated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Independence of events holds only if the CCD is not saturated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rate of event occurrence, $\lambda$, is constant over time. For example, the number of events occurring between $t$ and $t + \Delta t$ is $\lambda \Delta t$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The probability of an event in the interval ${t, t+\Delta t}$ is independent of previous events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The probability mass function (PMF) of the Poisson distribution is defined as:
$$
P(x; \lambda) = \frac{\lambda^x e^{-\lambda}}{x!}
$$
where $\lambda$ is the expected number of events in a given interval, and $x$ is the observed number of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Poisson distribution, the expected value (mean) is $\mu = \lambda$, and the variance is $\sigma^2 = \lambda$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;poisson-noise-shot-noise&#34;&gt;Poisson Noise (Shot Noise)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since $\sigma^2 = \lambda$, the standard deviation (Poisson noise) is $\sigma = \sqrt{\lambda}$. In photometry, where $N$ represents the number of photons hitting the CCD, this implies $\sigma = \sqrt{N}$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the characteristics of the Poisson distribution, the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) is calculated as follows:
$$
SNR = \frac{\mu}{\sigma} = \frac{\mu}{\sqrt{\mu}} = \sqrt{\mu}
$$
This relationship highlights the inherent noise properties in photon-counting measurements like those in CCD photometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radom Variables</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binomial</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/tutorials/astro-stat/2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Star Evolution in Different Environments: Filamentary, Fractal, Halo and Tidal-tail Clusters</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202307_binaryetar_evo_env_aj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202307_binaryetar_evo_env_aj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star-Crossed Lovers DI Tau A and B: Orbit Characterization and Physical Properties Determination</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202303_ditau_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202303_ditau_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamical Origin for the Collinder 132-Gulliver 21 Stream: A Mixture of three Co-Moving Populations with an Age Difference of 250 Myr</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202209_col132gul21_apjl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202209_col132gul21_apjl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Morphology of Open Clusters in the Solar Neighborhood with Gaia EDR3 II: Hierarchical Star Formation Revealed by Spatial and Kinematic Substructures</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202204_oc3dii_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202204_oc3dii_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disruption of Hierarchical Clustering in the Vela OB2 Complex and the Cluster Pair Collinder 135 and UBC 7 with Gaia EDR3: Evidence of Supernova Quenching</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202109_velob_apj-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202109_velob_apj-/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Water Latent Heat on the Thermal Structure of Ultra-Cool Objects: Brown Dwarfs and Free-Floating Planets</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202105_ydwarf_moist_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202105_ydwarf_moist_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGRINS RV: A Python Package for Precision Radial Velocities with Near-Infrared Spectra</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202104_igrinsrv_joss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202104_igrinsrv_joss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGRINS RV: A Precision RV Pipeline for IGRINS Using Modified Forward-Modeling in the Near-Infrared</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202104_igrinsrv_aj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202104_igrinsrv_aj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Morphology of Open Clusters in the Solar Neighborhood with Gaia EDR3: its Relation to Cluster Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202102_oc3d_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202102_oc3d_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Fates of Young Star Clusters After Gas Expulsion</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202006_ngc2232_apjl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202006_ngc2232_apjl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-Infrared Radial Velocity pipeline (IGRINS_RV)</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/near-infrared-radial-velocity-pipeline-igrins_rv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/near-infrared-radial-velocity-pipeline-igrins_rv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Cluster Dynamic Study</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/open-cluster-dynamic-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/open-cluster-dynamic-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y-dwarf Atmosphere Study</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/y-dwarf-atmosphere-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project/y-dwarf-atmosphere-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing the Stellar Population and Tidal Structure of the Blanco1 Star Cluster</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202001_blanco1_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/202001_blanco1_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of Tidal Tails in Disrupting Open Clusters: Coma Berenices and a Neighbor Stellar Group</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/201905_comaber_tail_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/201905_comaber_tail_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   **Two** 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of Stellar and Substellar Members in the Coma Berenices Star Cluster</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/201808_comber_apj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/publication/201808_comber_apj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project_example/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project_example/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Project</title>
      <link>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project_example/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shihyuntang.github.io/project_example/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
